Ashley Christian
Groundbreaker Marketing
Hey it's Ashley Christian
Welcome back to The #2 Septic Podcast
Usually we have guests on
but today is going to be a
solo episode
A lot of our friends are at
the WEQ show this week
and so some of the interviews that
we're working on
people that we're working on bringing
to the podcast
they're all busy this week with that
some of the biggest names in the
industry
So we're excited to have them on
in future episodes
but today you just get me
So today I thought it would be
really cool to answer some of your
most commonly asked questions
and these are actually questions
straight from our clients
We have a lot of septic clients
and we do a lot of communication
with them and so we basically took
all of our client communication we've
had in the last 30 days
and we found over 600 unique
questions which is an insane amount
of questions that our clients have
asked us
And we've come up with the top
most common themes
So we're going to answer those today
and I hope it's really helpful
All of those clients
they are paying us for marketing
services
So we're actually doing their
marketing for them
but then they're also paying us for
marketing advice and business advice
So we have a lot of questions
that come in regards to growing and
scaling a septic company and you know
what to do with marketing some of
the nuance there so I hope this
is really helpful for you if you're
a client and you're listening we're
not going to say any names or
give away who said what because that's
really confidential and we want to
keep that trust that we have with
our clients but hopefully it'll be
answer some questions that maybe you
didn't even think to ask
but actually could really benefit you
If you're not a client
you get basically a little slice of
what our clients pay for free
So I hope this really helps you
think about your business in a new
and different way and kind of expands
your belief about what's possible with
a septic business
And also your
just understanding of what the levers
are that you need to pull in
today's day and age in 2026 to
grow your business so we record all
of our client communication we don't
do it to be creepy we do
it because my brain cannot remember
over 600 questions a month it's just
it's impossible and so really to give
our clients the very best service
possible we have you know our email
our text phone calls and Zoom meetings
are all recorded with some sort of
AI and then it's filed into our
client's Google Drive folder that you
know no one gets access to that
it's all very my husband Josh
Christian makes sure that everything
is super super secure that's like his
specialty so no worries there but
what's great is that that's our source
of truth so if our client has
a preference for having something a
specific way if they have a very
specific goal let's say that their
goal is they're really wanting to work
on pumping calls specifically in a
specific area
Or like we have another client
they have some like service contracts
maintenance contracts a few of them
in a certain area of their state
that's kind of far away
And they really want to build up
the maintenance contracts in that area
so it's more dense so when they
send a truck out to go do
those maintenance routes it makes more
sense for them financially to get a
whole bunch and so that's a preference
and a goal specific to that company
that we're working on and targeting
that with the marketing that we're
doing so that's the kind of thing
that gets recorded in this folder for
them in their Google Drive so that
we're just making sure that we're
really serving them really well
So anyway we're able to pull all
these questions from all these
recordings and we have the most
common
So I'm excited to talk to you
guys about this and I hope it
gives you some insight that you've
never thought about before of what to
do with marketing your septic company
So number one most common question
that gets asked and a lot of
these are based on our own processes
things that we do as a marketing
agency that our clients have questions
about like why do you do it
that way what about this what about
that so this top question is we
strongly encourage all of our clients
to publish their pricing on their
website and so there's a lot of
questions surrounding that it is a
suggestion we don't require it I think
to date I've had one client that
doesn't want to publish their price in
for now which is totally fine
Everyone has their different reasons
and motivations and different set of
circumstances in their local area with
their competitors
But the reason that we strongly
encourage our clients to publish all
their prices is due to AI visibility
If you want to show up in
AI search the number one lever that
you can pull for that to happen
is to publish your prices on your
website
If you do that and your local
competitors are not publishing their
prices on their website
you are going to be the most
commonly referenced company in that AI
search like 100%
It's gonna be you if you publish
your prices and your competitors
aren't
So if you're listening to this
I hope you publish your prices on
your website or you ask us to
help you with it
and hopefully your surrounding
competitors don't hear this advice and
do the same thing
You wanna be the first to do
this
It really makes a huge difference in
the AI visibility
And AI visibility
AI is such a buzzword
but it really is greatly impacting the
way that septic companies market
themselves the way that our world
works
And so I don't wanna overblow it
just as a buzzword
but I want to be real with
what is happening
So we are seeing that our clients
are increasingly getting more and more
requests from someone like from
ChatGPT or Gemini or like the Google
AI search
And we actually track every single
phone call text message
website form that comes into our
clients businesses we track all of
them with attribution tracking so if
someone searches on ChatGPT and then
they call our customer or our client's
business we know about it so we
track that and we also have an
AI visibility tracker that we that we
built with AI but we use a
data source called DataForSEO and so
we pull directly from it basically it
will look at every
So every person that in that service
area it will go for each one
of the top four platforms and actually
pull real queries
So it will really actually do a
search
as if it was asking the question
about septic services in that specific
area
And then it gives us the list
of who's showing up first
second third fourth
fifth sixth
And so we have that list for
all of our clients
We track that our clients get a
dashboard and they have an AI
visibility tracker on there
It shows where they're performing in
comparison with their competitors
And I think our clients are pretty
much all dominating that I can think
of
Yeah I'm trying to think through some
specific instances but basically our
clients who are following the things
we're telling them to do
they're winning and they're dominating
on AI visibility and they're actually
getting leads and calls and website
forms into their business from AI so
that's that when I tell people that
they're usually like yeah let's
publish the prices so most of the
time people don't have an issue with
publishing the prices when they
understand what it does but more and
more Google is pushing people towards
showing your prices the more that you
show your prices the more you're going
to show up this is what Google
wants from you
So the more you do what Google
wants the more they're going to
reward you by showing you first
which is really the win of what
we're trying to get and grow the
business
So one of the questions that I've
had is what if
you know I'm not sure about
publishing my prices because then my
competitors are going to know what my
prices are
And then they're going to undercut me
you know by 50 bucks for a
pump out or whatever it is
so that's a question that clients have
asked is some of the top most
asked questions
And the answer to that is that
you're likely your competitors already
know what your prices are
It's probably not a secret
So I was talking to a client
one time
I can't even remember who it was
but they told me that they had
their I want to say it was
like their mother-in-law or their aunt
or somebody had essentially called
around to all the other local septic
companies in their area and just said
hey I need a
you know basically I need to pump
out
It's this that
and the other
you know what's your price?
And if you
if you pay attention or you're
if you're still closely connected to
what's going on with your phone calls
I've you've probably had phone calls
like that already that you're like
I think you kind of get a
feeling like I think this might be
someone from a competitor just trying
to find out our prices
that happens all day
every day
So my response to that is your
prices are not actually as secret as
you think they are
And so you're not doing anything with
your competitors
If you're publishing your prices
I did have a company ask about
they have they have a local
competitor who will basically over
inflate their prices and then give a
really big coupon
which is a strategy
I would say it's not a very
common strategy
It was actually the first time I've
heard of a company doing that
Like I want to say they priced
this and this wasn't one of my
clients
This is one of their competitors
They price their pump outs at like
1200 a pump out
which is a lot
And then but offered like a you
know limited time 500 off coupon so
essentially their pump outs end up
being like 700 which is still a
pretty healthy amount for a pump out
but this is a high income area
a high cost of living area so
that the prices weren't that off for
the high income area but that was
their question is like if I if
I don't do what they're doing is
that going to put me behind
and so I think I like to
always think of things as a customer
and it's hard when you own a
business put yourself in your
customer's shoes
But if I'm the customer and I'm
looking around at prices and I'm like
Oh like a $500 coupon
that sounds really good
If I'm the kind of customer that
doesn't doesn't shop around
I might just go for that
But if I'm the kind of customer
that's going to look at a couple
of different places and I see that
that's going to lower my trust in
that company because I
it's kind of like use car sales
or even just new car sales for
that matter
When
so my husband
I have five kids and they're all
driving now which is insane
Our our insurance bill every month is
like a mortgage
It's just the craziest thing
But anyway so we've done a lot
of car shopping recently and we really
prefer to go to places just as
customers where there's the price for
the car and sort of the price
is what you get
You have these places where it looks
higher but then there's room for like
finagling and haggling and wiggle
room
And then there's other places where
like they basically don't haggle
It's just a price
It's a really fair price
I think probably where the haggling
comes around is if you're getting like
a warranty or anything like that or
financing that's usually where they
end up haggling on it
but not the base price
So we really prefer to go to
the no haggle places is our huge
preference
And we've had a lot of car
shopping experience recently
So just as a consumer
that's our preference
And I think the same goes true
for not everyone
but most most of your customers are
looking for the same thing
They're just looking for transparency
They're looking for trust
when someone gets their septic system
serviced there's and we know everyone
listening to this right now and I
hope that none of our listeners are
this person but we all know that
there are not everyone out there in
the world is good people and there
are people who will go out there
and say that there's problems with a
system that there aren't really
problems or they'll say that there's
you know you need the whole system
replaced where really there's probably
a repair there's a repair first that
could be done rather than a
replacement just to chase the bottom
dollar it's kind of like if you
take your car in and you don't
know anything about cars you know it's
like is that mechanic going to be
truthful and honest or not so the
same thing is true with septic
services is that the more honest you
are you are going to build trust
and Google is all about trust that
is their number one thing that they
the reason that they show you first
is because they Google will trust you
they know that Google wants to keep
its users on its platform that's its
entire Google's entire business model
is keep people happy keep their users
happy they do that by recommending
businesses that are the have the
highest likelihood of treating their
customers well and so when they figure
when they have an algorithm that
decides who that is and who they're
going to show first they're looking
for trust your reviews is a huge
part of that but another huge part
of that is if you publish your
prices if you're up front with your
prices that is building trust with
Google and that that's why they're
recommending you first not only in AI
search but in regular search there's
also a feature on the Google Business
Profile this has been going around in
the home services now for especially
the last six months but we just
had our first client that actually had
a phone call like this
so it's still very much on the
brand new beginning frontier
but there is a button on the
Google Business Profile that if you're
a consumer if you're a homeowner
let's say or a business owner
small business owner
looking for someone to service your
septic system and you go on Google
there is a little button that says
get a quote
and if you push that button to
it's gonna actually have Google's AI
voice AI call four or five different
businesses and ask for it'll say this
is Google's AI service and it will
ask for a quote and then all
the businesses whether they don't
respond or they don't give a pricing
or they do it's going to give
that pricing send it back to the
customer that's out there looking for
services and so like I said we
had our first I think it was
about a month ago first call in
the wild in real life because we've
been hearing about this happening for
a long time we've seen it happen
in like HVAC electrical plumbing it's
been that's pretty pretty common there
so usually what happens in HVAC
electrical and plumbing with Google
happens there first and then it
trickles into other home services like
septic so what's really so that's part
of Google is pushing you to publish
your prices they they're even they're
building features into their products
that are all about price shopping so
publish your prices and if your
competitor
if you're worried about them
undercutting you but they're not
publishing their prices they're not
even going to show up in Google
so it doesn't matter I think there's
a lot of trust that gets built
when you publish those now another one
of the questions that I've had from
this I think we're just going to
probably get to the top most commonly
asked question here
which is about the pricing because
there's so much to go over there
There's such a deep dive
We'll definitely get into some of the
other commonly asked questions in
other segments
But another question that people had
is okay so if I publish my
prices they're really variable
right?
I have a lot of people who
will have a certain price depending on
the distance from their yard
You know it's wherever the pump
trucks live overnight
Or maybe it's not where the pump
trucks live
That's part of it
But where do they dump?
Where's their dump site?
And so you know
the price of diesel is insane
And the wear and tear on the
trucks and the time it gets to
go to different places
It really makes a big difference how
far you go out
especially with pumping
with some of the other services like
maintenance or locating or if you're
doing like an inspection or an
installation you can afford to go
further because the value that you're
getting like the monetary value you're
getting from those services quite a
bit higher than pumping pumping is
quite a bit lower and so it
really does you know it makes a
difference if you're going 30 minutes
away to go pump
or if you're going an hour and
15 minutes away
And so we have a lot of
our clients have different pricing
depending on the distance
And so that's a question
How do I put that on my
website?
If it's a variable or
you know we have different prices for
different size tanks
residential tanks
Of course if you're doing
if you're doing service on commercial
that's whole its whole own animal I
would really orient these prices
around your residential
and then you can say commercial you
know call us for a quote I
think that's fine I don't think you
need to publish your commercial prices
because those are so different it's
just a different animal completely so
really focus on the homeowner and then
it's fine to give a range if
you have the bottom and the top
of what you'll pump charge for pump
a pump out put that in there
or some people will do they'll do
you know it's x amount for the
first thousand gallons and then x
amount after that everyone has a
different way that they price and
there's a lot of different ways but
there's usually several tiers so it's
fine to just list the tiers it's
fine to say starting at your lowest
price and then not list anything else
The point here is not to get
super in the weeds about exactly which
prices you're publishing
but you're trying to basically get
just your prices out there
even if it's your starting price or
if it's a range
I have another client that they
actually priced out their installs
which I thought was great
So they have
I think they have like two basic
models that they install this
particular client and they have prices
on them so they put those prices
in there for the install job guarantee
you and I know because I've seen
like that's gotten them more install
jobs because they're putting it out
there and they're showing up on Google
in AI search because of that so
I think it's a good thing to
really not overthink sometimes it can
this is where clients get stuck as
they overthink it
and then they don't publish their
prices
Something else really cool that we can
do for our clients
So we now
we used to use WordPress
which was sort of the industry
standard for marketing agencies
Probably most of you have a WordPress
website
I think it's something like 45%
I know that's not an exact number
because I can't recall the exact
number but something along those
lines of the websites in the world
are built on WordPress
which is insane
so WordPress is definitely the giant
There are absolutely other ones that
you are maybe you have a Wix
website or Squarespace or Webflow
There's definitely other ones out
there
and so we used to build WordPress
websites but because of the day and
age of AI
we now build them on Astro which
is a static website and we build
it with Claude Code so it's if
those words mean nothing to you that's
totally fine it's just a modern way
of building a website and it's not
hard to do honestly I don't want
to make it sound like it's the
hardest thing in the world it's
actually much harder to build a
WordPress website than it is to build
an AI driven website
What's hard is to build a website
the right way that has the right
information
That's going to be the right trust
signals to Google so that you're
showing up first
And also that when someone does land
on your site
they're converting to a customer
There is a very specific formula that
we use
and what we do is we put
heat maps actually on our clients'
websites and we have a lot of
client websites
So the benefit we have in working
with so many different septic
companies is we have a lot of
data about what works and what doesn't
work
And we can continually tweaking that
where we can see
you know what's the conversion rate
of these different websites
And then we can analyze that
What you know
where are people dropping off?
Where are we losing people?
Where are we getting the higher
conversion rates?
Because we have things like reviews in
strategic places
We have click to call
There's a whole formula there
So the point of all that is
that that's how we build websites now
The other great thing about it is
they load super fast or lightning fast
to load which is one of
I think that's number three of the
top signals that Google uses to decide
how to rank your website is actually
your website speed
And all those old websites are
notoriously clunky and large and slow
And this is like super lightning fast
which is it makes a dramatic
difference in SEO
So but one of the really cool
things that we can do is we
can also do a pricing calculator on
there
Not that we have to
but it's just
it's a cool option that now it's
available if you wanted us to build
out a pricing calculator for your
pumping services and you had
different you have you had a lot
of different variables in there I mean
if you just have one price you
don't need a pricing calculator but if
you have a lot of variables that
is something we can build up pretty
simply which is really fun and also
is like it supercharges your AI
visibility so I'm just gonna stop
there I was gonna keep going but
I have 12 of the most common
questions and I think these need to
be their own little segments bite size
something you can listen to while
you're in the truck
But I hope that helps
And that's really a
what I just gave you
if we have any other marketing
agencies listening to this
I just gave them some of our
secret sauce right there
This is you know
my husband I as agency owners
we pay a good amount of money
every year for ongoing training so
that we stay on top of what's
happening because things change so
quickly
Google changes so quickly
the industry is marketing is always
changing
So one of the things we do
is we try to stay really on
top of what are those changes and
implement them
And so this is a newer thing
that we started this summer was
publishing prices
So it's pretty new
but one of the cool things about
that is that
all of our clients that were
previously paying for our services to
do SEO on their website
they were able to get this
We basically gave them this benefit of
adding prices to their website
without they didn't have to pay extra
for it
We just heard about it
We saw what a big difference it
made
And so we implemented it across the
board for all of our clients
But if you don't want to work
with us that's fine
because one of our missions is to
make marketing and business education
accessible to all septic companies
whether they work with us or work
with someone else or they DIY it
or they're just listening and don't do
anything which I hope you're not that
kind of person
But regardless of how you manage your
website I hope you put your pricing
on it
It's going to make a really big
difference
And that's
all I have for this segment
Thank you for joining me
And we will see you back next
week with one of our septic
influencers who has a huge TikTok
following and is also a client and
so that's super fun to be able
to work with this mystery person that
I'm going to introduce next week so
really excited to have them on and
they are currently speaking at the WEQ
show this week so that's why they're
not here but we have it scheduled
for next week
So I'm excited to talk more about
that and the story behind that and
more about this crazy subject
TikTok channel which is
it's really entertaining to watch
So thank you for being here
If you have any questions specifically
about your business
feel free to
give us a phone call or send
us a message
We just had a listener
just this past week
I was sitting at the airport called
and had some questions about their
business they've been listening and
you know I actually answer those phone
calls so if there's anything that we
can help you with pick up the
phone give us a call even if
I'm on a meeting and I can't
get back to you right away I
will call you back and happy to
chat with you